<root><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/osso-buco-gremolata</recipe_url><unique_id>1</unique_id><dish>Osso Buco Gremolata Recipe </dish><description>Osso buco gremolata is a Italian dish with veal shanks braised with vegetables that is garnished with gremolata. Get the recipe from PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/MSSC-305-Osso-Buco.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1/3 cup all-purpose flour</ingredient><ingredient>Coarse salt and freshly ground pepper</ingredient><ingredient>4 pieces veal shank, 3 inches thick (choose large-diameter pieces with broad marrow bones), tied with twine (about 7 pounds)</ingredient><ingredient>4 tablespoons unsalted butter</ingredient><ingredient>4 tablespoons olive oil</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup finely diced carrots</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup minced onion</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup finely diced celery</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup canned whole peeled tomatoes (about 5)</ingredient><ingredient>4 cups chicken stock</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup dry white wine</ingredient><ingredient>5 to 6 garlic cloves</ingredient><ingredient>1 dry bay leaf</ingredient><ingredient>8 sprigs fresh flat-leaf parsley, tied with twine</ingredient><ingredient>8 fresh basil leaves</ingredient><ingredient>For the Gremolata:</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon minced lemon zest</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon minced orange zest</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Preheat the oven to 300 degrees. In a large shallow dish  whisk together flour  1 tablespoon salt  and 1 ½ teaspoons pepper. Dredge the shanks in the mixture.</step><step>In a large heavy-bottomed pot or Dutch oven  melt 3 tablespoons butter with 3 tablespoons olive oil over medium-high heat. Brown the shanks on all sides. Remove from the pot and set aside.</step><step>Wipe out pot  and lower heat to medium-low. Add remaining tablespoon butter and oil. Add the carrots  onion  and celery to pan. Saute until mostly tender  8 to 10 minutes. Add the tomatoes  stock  and wine  simmer for 8 minutes  scraping the bottom of the pan.</step><step>Return the meat to the pot  add garlic  bay leaf  parsley  and basil. Cover and bake for 3 hours  or until meat is tender.</step><step>Remove the veal and set on a warm platter. Cover with foil to keep warm. Strain the cooking liquid through a fine mesh sieve and return liquid to pot. Reduce to 2 cups. Remove herbs from the vegetables and discard. Puree vegetables in a blender and return to pot (alternatively vegetables can be returned to the pot and pureed with an immersion blender).</step><step>To make the gremolata  mix together lemon and orange zest. To serve  place 1 shank on a warm plate and spoon some sauce over the meat. Garnish with gremolata.</step></directions><tags>Entree,Italian,Meat</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/one-pan-tomato-pasta</recipe_url><unique_id>2</unique_id><dish>One-Pan Tomato Pasta Recipe </dish><description>Try this one-pan tomato pasta recipe from Martha Stewart's Cooking School on PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/MSSC-304-OnePanTomatoPasta.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>12 ounces linguine</ingredient><ingredient>12 ounces cherry or grape tomatoes, halved or quartered if large</ingredient><ingredient>1 onion, thinly sliced (about 2 cups)</ingredient><ingredient>4 cloves garlic, thinly sliced</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 teaspoon red-pepper flakes</ingredient><ingredient>2 sprigs basil, plus torn leaves for garnish</ingredient><ingredient>2 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil, plus more for serving</ingredient><ingredient>Coarse salt and freshly ground pepper</ingredient><ingredient>4 1/2 cups water</ingredient><ingredient>Freshly grated Parmesan cheese, for serving</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Combine pasta  tomatoes  onion  garlic  red-pepper flakes  basil  oil  2 teaspoons salt  1/4 teaspoon pepper  and water in a large straight-sided skillet. Bring to a boil over high heat. Boil mixture  stirring and turning pasta frequently with tongs  until pasta is al dente and water has nearly evaporated  about 9 minutes.</step><step>Season to taste with salt and pepper  divide among 4 bowls  and garnish with basil. Serve with oil and Parmesan.</step></directions><tags>Entree,Italian,Family Friendly,Quick and Easy,Vegetarian,Pasta Recipes</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/butternut-squash-garlic-soup</recipe_url><unique_id>3</unique_id><dish>Butternut Squash and Garlic Soup Recipe </dish><description>This butternut squash and garlic soup recipe is a hearty side or a luscious main course on a cold night. Get the soup recipe from PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/butternut-squash-garlic-soup640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1.3 kilograms butternut squash (2.9 pounds)</ingredient><ingredient>1 small head garlic (40 grams/1.4 ounces)</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup extra virgin olive oil</ingredient><ingredient>2 teaspoons coarse sea salt (halve if using table salt)</ingredient><ingredient>3 cups water</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon tahini</ingredient><ingredient>toasted pumpkin seeds for garnish</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Preheat the oven to 390F </step><step>Peel the butternut squash using a vegetable peeler. Trim the ends off the squash and cut it in half lengthwise. Scrape out the seeds. Cut the halves in half again lengthwise (so that it's quartered). Slice each quarter into 1/4" thick pieces and add them to a bowl. </step><step>Remove the outer skin from the head of garlic  and break up the head into individual cloves  but do not peel the cloves. Add the garlic to the bowl with the butternut squash. </step><step>Toss the butternut squash and garlic with the olive oil and salt and then dump it all onto a baking sheet along with any oil and salt that's remaining in the bowl. Spread the squash around evenly and place them in the oven. </step><step>Roast the squash for 25-30 minutes  or until they are golden brown. You want to take them close to  but not quite burnt around the edges. </step><step>When the squash is done  remove it from the oven and pour 1 cup of water over it. Use a silicone spatula to scrape up the browned squash juices clinging to the pan. </step><step>When the garlic is cool enough to handle  peel the cloves and put them in a blender along with the squash  liquid in the pan  tahini  and another 2 cups of water. </step><step>Blend the soup until smooth and transfer to a pot to reheat before serving. </step><step>Serve garnished with toasted pumpkin seeds and lots of good bread. </step></directions><tags>Soup and Stew,Christmas,Thanksgiving,Comfort Food,Cooking for One,Family Friendly,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/blood-orange-granita</recipe_url><unique_id>4</unique_id><dish>Blood Orange Granita Recipe </dish><description>This blood orange granita recipe is quick, refreshing, and classy. Top with whipped cream for a easy dessert recipe from PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/blood-orange-granita640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1 1/2 cup water</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup sugar</ingredient><ingredient>6-7 sage leaves</ingredient><ingredient>8 blood oranges (about 1 3/4 cup), juiced and strained so the pulp is removed</ingredient><ingredient>For the barely sweet whipped cream:</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 cup heavy whipping cream</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoons powdered sugar, sifted</ingredient><ingredient>Pinch salt</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 teaspoon pure vanilla extract</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>In a medium saucepan  set over medium heat  pour in the water and sugar. Mix until the sugar dissolves. Add the sage leaves and when the syrup reaches a simmer  take the pan off the heat and allow the mixture to steep for 15-20 minutes. Remove the sage leaves and discard. </step><step>Pour the sage syrup into a 8 x 8 baking dish  along with the blood orange juice  and mix. Transfer to the freezer for an hour. Remove from the freezer  and using a fork  lightly scrape the ice crystals. Return to the freezer and repeat the scraping every 30 minutes for 3 to 4 hours. Repeat the occasional scrapping until the entire mixture is shaved. </step><step>To make the whipped cream  add all of the ingredients to a bowl and using a hand-mixer  beat until the cream forms soft peaks  about 2 to 3 minutes. </step><step>Divide the fluffy blood orange granita flakes between dessert cups and garnish with whipped cream  if desired. </step></directions><tags>Dessert,Christmas,Easter,New Year's Eve,Party,Thanksgiving,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Quick and Easy</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/roast-rack-of-lamb</recipe_url><unique_id>5</unique_id><dish>Roast Rack of Lamb Recipe </dish><description>Try Martha Stewart's recipe for roast rack of lamb from her PBS Food show called Martha Stewart's Cooking School.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/MSSC-303-rack-of-lamb.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>2</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>For the coating:</ingredient><ingredient>¾ cup lightly packed fresh flat-leaf parsley leaves</ingredient><ingredient>¾ cup fresh breadcrumbs (from 3 slices of bread, crusts removed)</ingredient><ingredient>½ cup lightly packed fresh mint leaves, plus whole sprigs for garnish</ingredient><ingredient>Finely grated zest of 1 lemon</ingredient><ingredient>1 garlic clove</ingredient><ingredient>1/3 cup extra-virgin olive oil</ingredient><ingredient>½ teaspoon coarse salt</ingredient><ingredient>For the lamb:</ingredient><ingredient>1 eight-rib frenched rack of lamb (1½ to 1¾ pounds), chine bone removed (for 	easier carving)</ingredient><ingredient>Coarse salt and freshly ground pepper</ingredient><ingredient>Olive oil</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon plus 1 teaspoon plain Greek-style yogurt</ingredient><ingredient>Mint jelly, for serving (optional)</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Heat oven to 400 degrees.</step><step>Let lamb rest at room temperature 1 hour  covered with plastic wrap. Place parsley  breadcrumbs  mint leaves  lemon zest  garlic  olive oil  and salt in a food processor and pulse to combine  scraping down sides of bowl as necessary  set aside.</step><step>Trim all but ¼ inch fat from lamb  then pat dry with paper towels. Season all over with salt and pepper. Heat a large (12-inch) saute pan over medium-high heat until hot  then add enough oil to just coat the bottom of the pan and heat until shimmering. Place lamb in pan fat side down  and sear until browned  2 to 3 minutes per side. Remove lamb from pan and let cool 10 minutes. Pour off excess fat from pan.</step><step>Use an offset spatula to spread yogurt evenly over browned (fat) side only  then top with breadcrumb mixture  pressing gently with your fingertips to adhere. Return to pan  coated side up. Roast until an instant-read thermometer registers 125 degrees (for medium-rare) when inserted through the eye (or midpoint of one side) of the rack  18 to 24 minutes. Let rest 10 minutes to allow temperature to rise and juices to redistribute. </step><step>Slice rack between bones and serve  with mint jelly if desired  and garnished with mint sprigs.</step></directions><tags>Entree,Christmas,Easter,Meat,Lamb Recipes,Roasting Recipes</tags></recipe><recipe /><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/balsamic-glazed-pearl-onions</recipe_url><unique_id>7</unique_id><dish>Balsamic-Glazed Pearl Onions Recipe </dish><description>Try this balsamic-glazed pearl onions recipe from Martha Stewart's Cooking School on PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/MSSC-302-Pearl-Onions.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>8</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>2 bags (10 ounces each) red or white pearl onions (or a combination of both)</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 cup dry white wine</ingredient><ingredient>3 tablespoons unsalted butter</ingredient><ingredient>Coarse salt and ground pepper</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup balsamic vinegar</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Bring a medium saucepan of water to a boil. Cut an X in stem end of each onion  and when water reaches a boil  place ones in water for one minute. Drain. Let stand until cool enough to handle  then carefully peel  leaving root and stem ends intact.</step><step>In a large skillet  combine onions  wine  butter  and 1 cup water  season with salt and pepper. Bring to a boil  then reduce to a simmer and cook until onions are tender and liquid has evaporated  about 15 minutes (if onions are large  increase cooking time and add more water).</step><step>Add vinegar and cook until sauce thickens and onions are glazed  2 to 3 minutes.</step></directions><tags>Side Dish,Christmas,Easter,Thanksgiving,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/steel-cut-porridge-with-honeyed-pecans</recipe_url><unique_id>8</unique_id><dish>Steel Cut Porridge with Honeyed Pecans </dish><description>You can make this steel cut porridge recipe from PBS Food for a quick, yet filling breakfast. Just add your favorite toppings such as honeyed pecans.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/steel-cut-porridge640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4-6</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>For the Honeyed Pecans:</ingredient><ingredient>3 tablespoons honey</ingredient><ingredient>pinch salt</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon brown sugar</ingredient><ingredient>1/3 cup pecans, roughly chopped</ingredient><ingredient>For the Steel Cut Oats:</ingredient><ingredient>3 tablespoons unsalted butter</ingredient><ingredient>3 cups steel cut oats</ingredient><ingredient>4 cups boiling water</ingredient><ingredient>2 teaspoons kosher salt</ingredient><ingredient>3/4 cup almond milk</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup light brown sugar</ingredient><ingredient>1 teaspoon ground cinnamon</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 teaspoon ground cardamom</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup cocoa nibs (as garnish)</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Let's start by making the honeyed pecans. To a small saucepan  pour in the honey and heat over medium low heat. Add a pinch of salt and brown sugar  mix until the sugar dissolves. Add the pecans and toss  coating them in the honey/sugar mixture. Transfer to a plate  spreading them out a bit (be careful--they'll be hot!) so they don't stick. Allow them to cool for 5 minutes. </step><step>In a medium saucepan  set over medium heat  add the butter. When the butter has melted  pour in the oats  stirring them until they're evenly coated in the butter  allow them to toast for about 3 minutes. Lower the heat to medium low and pour in the boiling water and salt  give the mixture a good mix and then cover the pot  cooking the oats for about 20 minutes. </step><step>Pour in almond milk  brown sugar  cinnamon and cardamom  gently stir the mixture and cook for an additional 10 minutes. Divide the porridge between bowls  and garnish them with a handful of the Honeyed Pecans  a sprinkling of cocoa nibs  a drizzle of honey and a spoonful of your favorite jam. </step></directions><tags>Breakfast and Brunch,Christmas,Easter,Thanksgiving,Comfort Food,Cooking for One,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/chicken-pot-pie-2</recipe_url><unique_id>9</unique_id><dish>Chicken Pot Pie Recipe </dish><description>Get Martha Stewart's recipe for chicken pot pie from her cooking show, Martha Stewart's Cooking School on PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/301-mscs-chicken640.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Stewart’s Cooking School</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>6</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1 whole chicken (3 ½ to 4 pounds)</ingredient><ingredient>5 tablespoons unsalted butter</ingredient><ingredient>1 pound Yukon gold potatoes, peeled and diced</ingredient><ingredient>3 medium carrots, peeled and diced</ingredient><ingredient>1 medium onion, peeled and diced</ingredient><ingredient>12 ounces cremini mushrooms, trimmed and quartered</ingredient><ingredient>1/3 cup cognac</ingredient><ingredient>5 tablespoons all-purpose flour</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup whole milk</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup fresh or frozen peas</ingredient><ingredient>2 tablespoons chopped fresh flat-leaf parsley</ingredient><ingredient>2 tablespoons fresh thyme leaves</ingredient><ingredient>Coarse salt and freshly ground pepper</ingredient><ingredient>1 ½ sheets frozen puff pastry, from 2 (14-ounce) boxes, thawed</ingredient><ingredient>1 large egg plus 1 egg yolk</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Place chicken in a large stockpot and add enough water to cover by 2 inches. Bring to a boil over medium-high heat  reduce to a simmer  and cook until chicken is cooked through (until an instant-read thermometer inserted into the thickest part registers 165 degrees)  about 50 minutes to 1 hour. Use tongs to remove chicken. When cool enough to handle  pull off and discard the skin  then separate the meat from the bones and tear into bite-size pieces. Reserve 2 cups of stock for the pot pie and the rest for another use.</step><step>In a large heavy-bottomed pot  melt butter over medium-high heat. Add potatoes  carrots  and onion. Cook  stirring occasionally  until potatoes and carrots are fork-tender  10 to 12 minutes. Add mushrooms  cooking until mushrooms are heated through. Add cognac and cook for 2 minutes. Add flour and cook  stirring  for 1 minute. Pour in reserved 2 cups chicken stock and milk. Bring to a simmer  cook  stirring constantly  until thick and bubbly  2 to 3 minutes. Stir in chicken  peas  parsley  and thyme. Season with salt and pepper. Ladle into six (12-ounce) ramekins  let cool.</step><step>Roll out thawed puff pastry on a lightly floured surface to a ¼-inch thickness. Cut out six circles that are 1 inch wider than ramekins or bowls being used. Cut a 1/2-inch vent hole in the center of each circle. Transfer puff pastry circles to a parchment-lined baking sheet and freeze for 20 minutes. </step><step>In a small bowl  whisk together egg  egg yolk  and 1 teaspoon water. Remove puff pastry circles from freezer. Top each ramekin with a puff pastry circle  crimping edges over sides to seal  and brush with egg wash. Transfer to refrigerator and chill for 30 minutes. </step><step>Preheat oven to 425 degrees. Transfer ramekins to a rimmed baking sheet. Bake until puff pastry is deep golden brown and filling is bubbling  20 to 25 minutes.</step></directions><tags>Entree,Christmas,Easter,Thanksgiving,Comfort Food,Poultry,Chicken Recipes,Pie Recipes</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/brioche-loaves</recipe_url><unique_id>10</unique_id><dish>Brioche Loaves Recipes </dish><description>Try this brioche loaves recipe from Martha Bakes featuring Martha Stewart's baking tips and techniques on PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2013/11/brioche640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>2</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>5 tablespoons lukewarm milk (100 to 115 degrees)</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 ounce fresh yeast</ingredient><ingredient>1 pound 2 ounces all-purpose flour, plus more for forming dough</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon coarse salt</ingredient><ingredient>6 large eggs</ingredient><ingredient>1 1/2 cups (3 sticks) unsalted butter, slightly softened, plus more for molds</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup superfine sugar</ingredient><ingredient>1 large egg yolk</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon milk</ingredient><ingredient>Nonstick cooking spray</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Place the milk and yeast in a small bowl  stir to dissolve. </step><step>Place the flour  salt  and eggs in the bowl of an electric mixer fitted with the dough hook attachment  add yeast mixture and mix on low speed to combine and knead  about 5 minutes. Scrape down sides of bowl with a spatula  knead on medium speed until smooth and elastic  about 10 minutes. </step><step>In a large bowl  mix together butter and sugar. Add a few small pieces of butter mixture to dough  with the mixer on low  add remaining butter mixture  a little bit at a time. When all the butter mixture has been added  increase speed and continue mixing until smooth  shiny  comes away from the sides of the bowl  and is elastic  6 to 10 minutes. </step><step>Butter a large bowl  transfer dough to prepared bowl  and cover with plastic wrap  let stand in a warm place until doubled in volume about 2 hours. </step><step>Lift dough from bowl and drop back into bowl to deflate  repeat process once or twice. Cover bowl and transfer to refrigerator to chill for at least 8 hours and up to overnight. </step><step>Butter two loaf pans that measure 8 1/2-by-4 1/2-inches across the top  and 7 1/2-by-3 1/2-inches across the base. Divide dough into 2 equal pieces. Divide each piece of dough into 8 equal pieces  form each piece into a ball. Place 8 balls of dough in each loaf pan  side-by-side. </step><step>In a small bowl  whisk together egg yolk and milk. Brush dough with egg yolk mixture  reserving remaining. Spray two pieces of plastic wrap with nonstick cooking spray  cover dough in both pans  cooking spray-side down and let stand in a warm place until doubled in volume  1 1/2 to 2 hours. </step><step>Preheat oven to 400 degrees on a convection oven and 425 degrees on a conventional oven. </step><step>Brush each loaf very lightly with reserved egg yolk mixture. Transfer pans to oven and bake until brioche just begins to turn golden  about 15 minutes. Reduce temperature to 350 degrees on a convection oven and 375 degrees conventional oven and continue baking until deep golden brown and internal temperature reaches 205 degrees on an instant-read thermometer  20 to 25 minutes more. </step><step>Remove from oven and let brioche cool in pans for 5 minutes. Unmold onto a wire rack and let cool completely. </step></directions><tags>Appetizer,Dessert,Side Dish,Christmas,Cookout,Easter,July 4th,New Year's Eve,Party,Picnic,Thanksgiving,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Vegetarian,Bread Recipes</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/country-carrot-slaw</recipe_url><unique_id>11</unique_id><dish>Country Carrot Slaw Recipe </dish><description>Here is a healthy take on our beloved coleslaw -- chock full of yummy fruits and veggies! Try this country carrot slaw recipe from PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/country-carrot-slaw640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings /><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>¼ cup of broccoli slaw or cabbage slaw</ingredient><ingredient>½ cup of shredded carrots</ingredient><ingredient>½ apple, sliced very thin</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp raisins</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp maple syrup</ingredient><ingredient>1 lemon squeeze</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Put all ingredients into a large bowl and toss until everything is coated evenly. Place in the refrigerator to chill  then enjoy!</step></directions><tags>Side Dish,Cookout,July 4th,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Healthy,Quick and Easy,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/non-fat-milk-fruit-shake</recipe_url><unique_id>12</unique_id><dish>Non-Fat Milk Fruit Shake Recipe </dish><description>This non-fat milk fruit shake recipe is a healthy, fruity treat on a hot day is sure to please anyone looking for a cool snack. Get the recipe at PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/milk-fruit-shake640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings /><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1 cup of skim milk</ingredient><ingredient>½ cup of ice</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp of sucralose</ingredient><ingredient>½ cup of strawberries</ingredient><ingredient>1 tsp of strawberry preserves</ingredient><ingredient>½ tsp of vanilla bean or extract</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Pull all green leaves off of your strawberries. </step><step>Saving one strawberry on the side  combine all of the ingredients in a blender and blend with the ice until it is smooth and creamy. </step><step>Pour the mixture in a glass and garnish with the remaining strawberry.</step></directions><tags>Beverage,Snack,Cooking for One,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Quick and Easy,Smoothie Recipes</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/banana-snack-wraps</recipe_url><unique_id>13</unique_id><dish>Banana Snack Wraps Recipe </dish><description>Try these healthy banana snack wraps recipe. It is kid-approved and a delicious snack. Get the recipe at PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/banana-snack-wraps640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings /><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>1 whole grain wrap</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp creamy peanut butter</ingredient><ingredient>1 banana, peeled</ingredient><ingredient>toothpicks</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Place the whole grain wrap on a plate and cover it with the peanut butter. </step><step>Take the peeled banana and place it on the wrap. Roll the wrap around the banana  then slice it into one-inch slices. Put a toothpick through each slice to hold the wrap onto the banana. </step><step>Serve them cold or heat in a microwave for a real treat!</step></directions><tags>Snack,Cooking for One,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Healthy,Quick and Easy,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/sliced-apples-with-apple-dip</recipe_url><unique_id>14</unique_id><dish>Sliced Apples with Apple Dip </dish><description>Chef Rob Stinson makes sliced apples and apple dip for a great snack that is healthy too. Get the recipe at PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/sliced-apples-apple-dip640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Ed Said</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings /><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>8 oz of cream cheese</ingredient><ingredient>¼ cup of natural applesauce</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp of maple syrup or honey</ingredient><ingredient>1 apple</ingredient><ingredient>1 lemon</ingredient><ingredient>1 tbsp of sugar substitute</ingredient><ingredient>½ tsp of vanilla bean or extract</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup of water</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Pour the water into a bowl. Squeeze the juice of the lemon into the water. </step><step>Slice your apple into thin slices  leaving the skin on. Place the slices into the water. Allow the bowl to chill in the refrigerator – this will keep the apple slices from turning brown. </step><step>In a separate bowl  combine all other ingredients and mix until they are even  smooth and one color. Dip apple slices in the mixture and enjoy!</step></directions><tags>Snack,Cookout,New Year's Eve,Party,Picnic,Cooking for One,Cooking with Kids,Family Friendly,Healthy,Quick and Easy,Vegetarian</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/hijiki-salad</recipe_url><unique_id>15</unique_id><dish>Hijiki Salad Recipe </dish><description>This hijiki salad is made with some dried sea vegetables, frozen legumes and a root vegetable. Get the recipe from PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/hijiki-salad640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Fresh Tastes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>4</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>20 grams dried hijiki</ingredient><ingredient>2 teaspoons lemon juice</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon soy sauce</ingredient><ingredient>1 teaspoon olive oil</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 teaspoon salt</ingredient><ingredient>50 grams carrots, shredded</ingredient><ingredient>80 grams shelled edamame (about 1/2 cup)</ingredient><ingredient>1 tablespoon toasted sesame seeds</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Put the hijiki in a bowl and wash. </step><step>Cover with cold water and let the hijiki soak for 10 minutes. </step><step>In a small bowl  whisk together the lemon juice  soy sauce  olive oil  and salt. </step><step>Drain the hijiki well in a wire mesh sieve and use your hands to press out any extra water. </step><step>Add the hijiki to a bowl with the carrots  edamame and sesame seeds. </step><step>Pour the dressing over the vegetables and toss to combine. </step></directions><tags>Salad,Side Dish,Japanese,Healthy</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/lemon-souffle</recipe_url><unique_id>16</unique_id><dish>Lemon Soufflé Recipe </dish><description>These individual souffles are easier to make than you might think. To help them rise properly, use upward brush strokes to butter the dishes.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/lemon-souffle640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>6</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>2 tablespoons unsalted butter, plus more, room temperature, for dishes</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 cup granulated sugar, plus more for dishes</ingredient><ingredient>8 large egg yolks plus 10 large egg whites, room temperature</ingredient><ingredient>2 tablespoons all-purpose flour</ingredient><ingredient>1/4 cup plus 2 tablespoons fresh lemon juice (from 2 lemons), plus 2 tablespoons finely grated lemon zest</ingredient><ingredient>1 cup whole milk</ingredient><ingredient>Garnish: confectioners' sugar</ingredient></ingredients><directions><step>Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Butter six 12-ounce souffle dishes  and then dust with granulated sugar. Whisk together yolks  flour  zest  and 2 tablespoons granulated sugar. </step><step>Bring milk to a boil in a small saucepan. Slowly pour milk into yolk mixture  whisking constantly to prevent yolks from cooking. Return mixture to pan  and whisk until thick like a pudding  1 to 2 minutes. Strain through a sieve  and whisk in butter and lemon juice. </step><step>Beat whites until foamy. Gradually add remaining 1/4 cup plus 2 tablespoons granulated sugar  and beat until stiff peaks form. Stir a third of the whites into the yolk mixture. Gently fold in the remaining whites using a rubber spatula. </step><step>Fill each souffle dish to the top  and smooth. Run your thumb around edges to remove batter from rims. </step><step>Bake on a rimmed baking sheet until souffles rise and are golden  about 16 minutes. Dust with confectioners' sugar  and serve immediately  before souffles lose their height. </step></directions><tags>Dessert</tags></recipe><recipe><recipe_source>www.pbs.org/food/recipes</recipe_source><recipe_url>http://www.pbs.org/food/recipes/apple-tarte-tatin-2</recipe_url><unique_id>17</unique_id><dish>Apple Tarte Tatin Recipe </dish><description>Make Martha Stewart's recipe for apple tarte tatin from the Tarts and Tartlets episode of Martha Bakes on PBS Food.</description><categories>NULL</categories><recipe_author>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</recipe_author><recipe_image>http://www.pbs.org/food/wp-content/blogs.dir/2/files/2014/01/apple-tart-tatin640x360.jpg</recipe_image><photo_credit>Recipe courtesy of Martha Bakes</photo_credit><recipe_prep_time /><recipe_total_time /><recipe_cook_time>NULL</recipe_cook_time><special_equipment>null</special_equipment><rating>null</rating><servings>9-</servings><recipe_calories>NULL</recipe_calories><ingredients><ingredient>5 to 6 medium apples, such as Braeburn</ingredient><ingredient>3/4 cup granulated sugar</ingredient><ingredient>3 tablespoons water</ingredient><ingredient>4 tablespoons (1/2 stick) unsalted butter, cut into small pieces</ingredient><ingredient>1/2 recipe for pate brisee</ingredient><ingredient /></ingredients><directions><step>Halve and core apples. Set aside one half. Quarter remaining apples and transfer to a large bowl. Squeeze lemon over apple slices and set aside. </step><step>Combine sugar and water in a 9-inch cast-iron skillet. Bring mixture to a boil over medium-high heat  immediately reduce heat to medium and cook until mixture begins to thicken and turn amber. Remove from heat and stir in butter. </step><step>Place reserved apples in center of skillet. Decoratively arrange remaining apple slices  cut side up  in skillet around reserved apples. Continue layering slices until level with top of skillet. Cut any remaining apples into thick slices to fill in gaps. If fruit does not completely fill pan  tart will collapse when inverted. </step><step>Place skillet over low heat and cook until syrup thickens and is reduced by half  about 20 minutes. Do not let syrup burn. Remove from heat and let cool. </step><step>Preheat oven to 375 degrees. Line a baking sheet with parchment paper  set aside. </step><step>Roll out pate brisee to a 10- to 11-inch circle  about 1/8 inch thick  transfer to a baking sheet and chill until firm  about 30 minutes. </step><step>Place pate brisee over apples and tuck edges. Transfer skillet to prepared baking sheet  transfer baking sheet to oven and bake until golden brown  about 35 minutes. Transfer to a wire rack and let cool 15 to 20 minutes. Loosen pastry from skillet using a sharp knife. Place a rimmed platter over skillet  quickly and carefully invert. Serve immediately. </step></directions><tags>Dessert,French,Christmas,New Year's Eve,Thanksgiving</tags></recipe></root>